<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<books>
  <book ID="CryptitesACatalogueOfStrangeAndAstoundingRocks" Title="{{W|Cryptites: A Catalogue of Strange and Astounding Rocks}}" Format="Auto" Margins="1,2,2,2">
    <page>
By {{W|Prozeman Schorl Hagad}}

Collected here are the stories and folklore surrounding some of the more well-known and salient cryptites. My own opinions, in brief, are offered on the topic as well.

May these tales inspire you to find wonder in rocks and the wider world.
    </page>
    <page>
{{W|Elsewhere Mica}}

There is a widely shared story of a tinkerer of the desert village of Urvakesh who built artisanal lanterns. They scrounged whatever uniquely colored glass they could for these light-boxes, and also experimented with using other materials in their construction. One day, a travelling scavenger passed through the village and, among the scrap they bartered away for fresh ammunition, was a selection of truly scintillating plates of mica. The tinkerer eagerly fell to the task of constructing a set of lanterns using this intriguing crystal.

But when the oil-wicks were lit, the light which poured from the new lanterns illuminated things which were not there. One lantern revealed stands of dew-soaked, vine-wrapped, trees. Another showed gleaming lattices of soft-white metal sprouting from flaming, bulbous corals. These visions glistened in the flickering light but vanished when the flames were doused.

For a time, these lanterns were played with as a strange oddity, the villagers delighting in the sights of distant elsewheres. But then one of them saw a moving shape in the lantern-light images and shortly afterwards their head detonated. The tinker then smashed the offending lanterns and ground their lenses into dust.

This theoretical mica has since been dubbed Elsewhere Mica by cryptogeologists. I have journeyed to Urvakesh myself, and this story is still told by its denizens. The lantern tinker has since, sensibly, moved elsewhere and any remaining mica dust has long been lost to the winds, but I find only minor inconsistencies in the village's retellings. It seems plausible that Elsewhere Mica existed, though there is terribly little known about possible extant deposits.
    </page>
    <page>
{{W|Winestone}}

One year ago, a party of four, while traveling from Suxermasp Orchard through a canyon at Hindsun, noticed strange streaks of discoloration on the canyon walls. Upon closer inspection, they found that small quantities of heady wine were dripping out of cracks in the stone. While celebrating the find and collecting the wine, a pack of snapjaws arrived and drove the party to retreat to a more defensible position. Since, they have claimed they discovered a previously unheard-of rock that secretes wine.

While intriguing, one must consider the fungus known as weeps. Different varieties of these unique growths are known to exude all manner of fluids, including something analogous to wine. Owing to the porous nature of the shale and limestone which is found in these canyons, and the depths to which a weep's mycelia can reach, the hypothesis that the presence of a wine-secreting weep caused a saturation of wine in the rock has been put forth.

Members of the party have dismissed this theory, insisting they "saw no funguses". Attempts to return to the site have proven difficult as the members of the party have conflicting accounts as to the route they took through the canyon.

Given this, and the existence of a plausible counterhypothesis, it is the opinion of this cryptogeologst that Winestone is most likely hearsay and not of legitimate scientific interest.
    </page>
    <page>
{{W|Neurolith}}

Four years ago, a Mechanist expedition explored the ruins of Brown Apeirogon Tekesh in the Moghra'yi. Though nothing of great value or interest was found on the surface, a psychically attuned member of the party felt some astral perturbations emanating from below. This esper insisted on finding the source of these psychic signals, but after two days of searching no sign of psychic life nor entrance to a hidden chamber in the ruins was found. During this time, the esper grew increasingly convinced that "the rocks were speaking to them" and the expedition then left the ruins for the sake of their member's health.

This story, along with similar tales from psychically sensitive individuals detecting strange signals from within rock formations corroborates the theory of the existence of a psychically active crystalline structure, dubbed Neurolith by cryptogeologists. Leading theories on the nature of Neurolith include it being an advanced form of structural degeneration experienced by truly ancient cragsmench luminaries, an extradimensional incursion from border-realities where rocks have learned to think, or possibly a wayward deposit from the crystalline tree Chavvah of the Moon Stairs.

Given the geographic distance between reports, and the typical ambiguity of psychic matters, it is possible, and indeed likely in my own opinion, that encounters with Neurolith will end up being discovered to be explained by a range of underexplored phenomena, rather than a single, ubiquitous psychic crystalline structure.
    </page>
    <page>
{{W|Skunkschist}}

There is a legend passed around caravan campfires of a rock that smells so vile it will inflict queasiness and retching in any who catch a whiff. Supposedly, this is a stone which is quarried by certain creatures who lack olfactory senses and installed as wards against intrusion to protect valuable stashes. If the smell of a cave turns your stomach, there must surely be something good within.

As should be well known by any arconaut, hermit, or misfortunate visitor of Golgotha, there are countless reasons a cave can be smelly. Moreover, the smell-less species varies between accounts from different regions of Qud. The legend of Skunkschist strikes this cryptogeologist as a tall tale intended to goad the foolish into hygienically sabotaging situations, and nothing more.
    </page>
    <page>
{{W|Doomstone}}

The existence of Doomtone was first recorded by Yakat of Two Minds thirty years ago, though it would take two more years until their findings would be themselves uncovered. Based upon their posthumously recovered journal, while exploring several strata deep, Yakat discovered an unfamiliar glassy grey layer directly below a deposit of salt-heavy minerals corresponding to when the first Gyre blighted the land. This strange deposit defied classification or explanation, but while Yakat examined it, they developed headaches and a fever. Their yuckwheat proved insufficient to treat the disease, and before they could leave the cave system to seek further medical aid, they tragically perished.

There are at least two other records of arconaut expeditions descending into deep strata, finding an unfamiliar glassy grey stone, and shortly thereafter perishing under mysterious circumstances. Were the explorers of Qud not so studious with their journal-keeping, we likely would not know of the existence of this rock of ill-portent.

Some have, rather romantically, wondered if Doomstone deposits could be found preceding every great calamity in the geologic record. This would correspond with Yakat's findings, and more loosely fit with the less geologically descriptive records of the arconauts. Another romantic musing is that only doomed individuals are themselves capable of finding this stone. Regardless, given that no cryptogeological expedition which has sought out Doomstone has returned, it is strongly recommended that one avoids this baleful mineral, whatever its true nature may be.
    </page>
  </book>
  <book ID="CRYPTOGEOLOGY_SharingLesson" Title="{{G|Lesson of Life-circling}}">
    <page>
Small-squirmer, coils circle all earth and stone and soil and clay to stir-sieve. Other circles round earth. Crawls with life-things. Brood-kin carve circles to stir-sieve. Circles within circles. Richness seeks well-circled soil. Carve betwixt the life-thing growths or circle salt and self-waste.
    </page>
  </book>
  <book ID="CRYPTOGEOLOGY_CalmLesson" Title="{{B|Lesson of Rock-life}}">
    <page>
Small-squirmer, life-things smaller still. Grains of earth-veins. Coils and gullet and rage stir-under all. But rage-lived like above-heat. Calm, small-squirmer. Rock-lived, you are as world sheet. Risk not heat-rage.
    </page>
  </book>
  <book ID="CRYPTOGEOLOGY_WonderLesson" Title="{{M|Lesson of Wonder-whys}}">
    <page>
Small-squirmer, fresh-hunger sated by time. Crustal-rupture grow cold. Hunger-reigns digest to freedom. Wonder-whys enter head. Why eat? Why carve? Why self? Coil tight wonder. Never shed. Follow answers. Become joy split. Become dream filled.
    </page>
  </book>
  <book ID="CRYPTOGEOLOGY_DistrustLesson" Title="{{R|Lesson of Ruler-thing Distrust}}">
    <page>
Small-squirmer, trust not ruler-things. Flesh-metal ruler-things helped become Egg-Bearer. But many eggs make them fear-reigned. They twist, poison dreams and eggs. Ruler-things fear-lived, deceit-plated. Trust not. Make caution when devouring; they poison.
    </page>
  </book>
</books>
